=== [1] ===
CN:     尊敬的{{先生|女士}}，这里可以乘坐前往廷根湖的长途马车！
Old EN: Respected {Mr.{ Ms.|}}, you can take a long-distance carriage to Tingen Lake here!
New EN: Respected {{Mr.|Ms.}}, you can take a long-distance carriage to Tingen Lake here!
Cur RU: Уважаемый {Mr.{ Ms.|}}, здесь вы можете сесть в междугородний экипаж до озера Тинген!

=== [2] ===
CN:     ……我知道，让我一个人呆着吧，{{先生|女士}}。
Old EN: ...I know, let me be alone, {Mr.{Ms.|}}.
New EN: ...I know, let me be alone, {{Mr.|Ms.}}.
Cur RU: ...Я знаю, оставь меня одного, {Mr.{Ms.|}}.

=== [3] ===
CN:     你也觉得是我做错了，对不对……{{先生|女士}}，我想拜托你一件事，如果你在铁十字街见到我的父亲贝尔曼先生，请帮我瞒着他，谢谢您。
Old EN: You also think I did something wrong, don't you... {Mr.{ Ms.|}}, I want to ask a favor of you. If you see my father, Mr. Bellman, on Iron Cross Street, please help me keep it from him. Thank you.
New EN: You also think I did something wrong, don't you... {{Mr.|Ms.}}, I want to ask a favor of you. If you see my father, Mr. Bellman, on Iron Cross Street, please help me keep it from him. Thank you.
Cur RU: Ты тоже думаешь, что я сделал что-то не так, не так ли... {Mr.{ Ms.|}}, я хочу попросить тебя об одолжении. Если вы увидите моего отца, мистера Беллмана, на Айрон-Кросс-стрит, пожалуйста, помогите мне скрыть это от него. Спасибо.

=== [4] ===
CN:     欢迎来到廷根，{{先生|女士}}！要乘马车吗？可以到达廷根的任何地方，还为您提供免费的讲解服务！
Old EN: Welcome to Tingen, {Mr.{ Ms.|}}! Would you like to take a carriage? It can reach anywhere in Tingen, and we even provide free guide services!
New EN: Welcome to Tingen, {{Mr.|Ms.}}! Would you like to take a carriage? It can reach anywhere in Tingen, and we even provide free guide services!
Cur RU: Добро пожаловать в Тинген, {Mr.{ Ms.|}}! Хотите взять карету? Он может добраться до любой точки Тингена, и мы даже предоставляем бесплатные услуги гида!

=== [5] ===
CN:     好心的{{先生|女士}}，多给点吧……还有好些个孩子没饭吃……
Old EN: Kind {Mr.{ Ms.|}}, please give a little more... there are still many children who have nothing to eat...
New EN: Kind {{Mr.|Ms.}}, please give a little more... there are still many children who have nothing to eat...
Cur RU: Добрый {Mr.{ Ms.|}}, дайте, пожалуйста, еще немного... еще много детей, которым нечего есть...

=== [6] ===
CN:     这位{{先生|小姐}}，或许您能帮帮曼妮莎……哦，可是您也并不知情呀！
Old EN: This {Mr.{ Ms.|}}, perhaps you could help Manisha... Oh, but you don't know anything about it either!
New EN: This {{Mr.|Ms.}}, perhaps you could help Manisha... Oh, but you don't know anything about it either!
Cur RU: Этот {Mr.{ Ms.|}}, возможно, вы могли бы помочь Манише... О, но вы тоже ничего об этом не знаете!

=== [7] ===
CN:     {{先生|女士}}，是你啊，你买的商品退货成功，货款已经拿回来了。
Old EN: {Mr.{ Ms.|}}, it's you. The return of the goods you purchased was successful, and the payment has been retrieved.
New EN: {{Mr.|Ms.}}, it's you. The return of the goods you purchased was successful, and the payment has been retrieved.
Cur RU: {Mr.{ Ms.|}}, это вы. Возврат купленного вами товара прошел успешно, и оплата получена.

=== [8] ===
CN:     前往<h>廷根火车站</>
Old EN: Go to <h>Tingen Train Station</h>
New EN: Go to <h>Tingen Train Station</>
Cur RU: Перейти на железнодорожный вокзал <h>Тинген</h>

=== [9] ===
CN:     真是一次成功的<h>【铁路大亨】</>
Old EN: What a successful <h>[Railroad Tycoon]</h>
New EN: What a successful <h>[Railroad Tycoon]</>
Cur RU: Какой успешный <h>[Железнодорожный магнат]</h>

=== [10] ===
CN:     晋升完成了，可以离开<h>黑荆棘安保公司</>了
Old EN: The advancement is complete; you can leave the <h>Blackthorn Security Company</h> now.
New EN: The advancement is complete; you can leave the <h>Blackthorn Security Company</> now.
Cur RU: Продвижение завершено; вы можете покинуть <h>Охранная компания «Чёрный Чертополох»</h> прямо сейчас.

=== [11] ===
CN:     {{先生|女士}}，你看起来不像个有钱人，我事先提醒一句，这里一杯酒的价格很可能让你一件衣服都不剩！
Old EN: {Mr.{ Ms.|}}, you don't look like a rich person. I'll give you a heads-up: the price of a drink here might very well leave you without a single piece of clothing!
New EN: {{Mr.|Ms.}}, you don't look like a rich person. I'll give you a heads-up: the price of a drink here might very well leave you without a single piece of clothing!
Cur RU: {Mr.{ Ms.|}}, вы не похожи на богатого человека. Предупреждаю: цена напитка здесь вполне может оставить вас без единого предмета одежды!

=== [12] ===
CN:     科、科尔沁，算了吧。<P_Heart>（小声）</>再闹下去，估计明天连这点儿也要没了……
Old EN: Ke, Kerqin, let it go. <P_Heart>(Whispering)</P_Heart> If you keep making a scene, I doubt we'll even have this much left by tomorrow...
New EN: Ke, Kerqin, let it go. <P_Heart>(Whispering)</> If you keep making a scene, I doubt we'll even have this much left by tomorrow...
Cur RU: Ке, Керкин, оставь это. <P_Heart>(шепотом)</P_Heart> Если ты продолжишь устраивать сцену, сомневаюсь, что к завтрашнему дню у нас останется хотя бы столько...

=== [13] ===
CN:     {{先生|女士}}，您看见那位女士了吗？妈妈叫孩子回家吃饭，多美好的风景。
Old EN: {Mr.{ Ms.|}}, have you seen that lady? A mother calling her child home for dinner—what a beautiful scene.
New EN: {{Mr.|Ms.}}, have you seen that lady? A mother calling her child home for dinner—what a beautiful scene.
Cur RU: {Mr.{ Ms.|}}, вы видели эту женщину? Мать зовет ребенка домой на ужин – какая прекрасная сцена.

=== [14] ===
CN:     回想<h>生活费</>的位置
Old EN: Recall the location of the <h>living expenses</h>
New EN: Recall the location of the <h>living expenses</>
Cur RU: Напомним расположение <h>расходы на проживание</h>

=== [15] ===
CN:     {{先生|女士}}，请问您去过贝克兰德吗？
Old EN: {Mr.{ Ms.|}}, may I ask if you have ever been to Backlund?
New EN: {{Mr.|Ms.}}, may I ask if you have ever been to Backlund?
Cur RU: {Mr.{ Ms.|}}, могу ли я спросить, были ли вы когда-нибудь в Баклунде?

=== [16] ===
CN:     前往中庭<h></>
Old EN: Go to the atrium <h></h>
New EN: Go to the atrium <h></>
Cur RU: Идите в атриум <h></h>.

=== [17] ===
CN:     但我不理解，{{先生|女士}}，你不认为爱情只是命运的捉弄吗？怎么会有一见钟情这样荒谬的事，让人愿意为陌生人付出一切呢？
Old EN: But I don't understand, {Mr.{ Ms.|}}, don't you think love is just a trick of fate? How can there be such an absurd thing as love at first sight that makes people willing to give everything for a stranger?
New EN: But I don't understand, {{Mr.|Ms.}}, don't you think love is just a trick of fate? How can there be such an absurd thing as love at first sight that makes people willing to give everything for a stranger?
Cur RU: Но я не понимаю, {Mr.{ Ms.|}}, тебе не кажется, что любовь - это просто игра судьбы? Как может существовать такая абсурдная вещь, как любовь с первого взгляда, которая заставляет людей отдать все ради незнакомца?

=== [18] ===
CN:     欢迎你，{{先生|女士}}。我是萨默尔太太，很高兴你能来。
Old EN: Welcome, {Mr.{ Ms.|}}. I am Mrs. Sammer, I am very glad you could come.
New EN: Welcome, {{Mr.|Ms.}}. I am Mrs. Sammer, I am very glad you could come.
Cur RU: Добро пожаловать, {Mr.{ Ms.|}}. Я миссис Сэммер, я очень рада, что вы смогли прийти.

=== [19] ===
CN:     前往<h>占卜家俱乐部</>
Old EN: Go to the <h>Divination Club</h>
New EN: Go to the <h>Divination Club</>
Cur RU: Перейти в клуб гадания <h></h>

=== [20] ===
CN:     {{先生|女士}}，你看看它叫什么？它叫猫！
Old EN: {Mr.{ Ms.|}}, look at what it's called? It's called a cat!
New EN: {{Mr.|Ms.}}, look at what it's called? It's called a cat!
Cur RU: {Mr.{ Ms.|}}, посмотрите, как он называется? Это называется кот!

=== [21] ===
CN:     您好，{{先生|女士}}！您要买车票吗？
Old EN: Hello, {Mr.{ Ms.|}}! Would you like to buy a ticket?
New EN: Hello, {{Mr.|Ms.}}! Would you like to buy a ticket?
Cur RU: Здравствуйте, {Mr.{ Ms.|}}! Хотите купить билет?

=== [22] ===
CN:     {{先生|女士}}，我有一件很重要的事情告诉你！
Old EN: {Mr.{ Ms.|}}, I have something very important to tell you!
New EN: {{Mr.|Ms.}}, I have something very important to tell you!
Cur RU: {Mr.{ Ms.|}}, я хочу сказать вам кое-что очень важное!

=== [23] ===
CN:     制作神话武器的关键材料。\n\n开启神话铸造仪式时，需要消耗1个<Highlight>神话织茧</>和60个<Highlight>织茧游丝</>，完成仪式后，获得神话武器<Highlight>【隐秘之拥】</>。\n若是缺少<Highlight>神话织茧</>，也可消耗30个<Highlight>织茧游丝</>，铸造武器<Highlight>【夜幕之颂】</>。<Highlight>【夜幕之颂】</>可通过补齐材料进一步铸造为<Highlight>【隐秘之拥】</>。\n随赛季进程，将开放【隐秘之拥】和【夜幕之颂】的装等提升，提升时消耗一定数量的<Highlight>织茧游丝</>。
Old EN: Key materials for crafting Mythical weapons.\n\nWhen initiating a Mythical Forging ritual, it consumes 1 <Highlight>Mythical Cocoon</Highlight> and 60 <Highlight>Cocoon Silk Strands</Highlight>. Upon completing the ritual, you will obtain the Mythical weapon <Highlight>[Secret Embrace]</Highlight>.\nIf you lack a <Highlight>Mythical Cocoon</Highlight>, you may instead consume 30 <Highlight>Cocoon Silk Strands</Highlight> to forge the weapon <Highlight>[Ode to Nightfall]</Highlight>. <Highlight>[Ode to Nightfall]</Highlight> can be further forged into <Highlight>[Secret Embrace]</Highlight> by providing the missing materials.\nAs the season progresses, the gear level cap for [Secret Embrace] and [Ode to Nightfall] will be increased, which will consume a certain amount of <Highlight>Cocoon Silk Strands</Highlight>.
New EN: Key materials for crafting Mythical weapons.\n\nWhen initiating a Mythical Forging ritual, it consumes 1 <Highlight>Mythical Cocoon</> and 60 <Highlight>Cocoon Silk Strands</>. Upon completing the ritual, you will obtain the Mythical weapon <Highlight>[Secret Embrace]</>.\nIf you lack a <Highlight>Mythical Cocoon</>, you may instead consume 30 <Highlight>Cocoon Silk Strands</> to forge the weapon <Highlight>[Ode to Nightfall]</>. <Highlight>[Ode to Nightfall]</> can be further forged into <Highlight>[Secret Embrace]</> by providing the missing materials.\nAs the season progresses, the gear level cap for [Secret Embrace] and [Ode to Nightfall] will be increased, which will consume a certain amount of <Highlight>Cocoon Silk Strands</>.
Cur RU: Ключевые материалы для создания мифического оружия.\n\nПри запуске ритуала мифической ковки расходуется 1 <Highlight>Мифический кокон</Highlight> и 60 <Highlight>Шелковые нити кокона</Highlight>. По завершении ритуала вы получите Мифическое оружие <Highlight>[Тайное объятие]</Highlight>.\nЕсли у вас нет <Highlight>Мифический кокон</Highlight>, вместо этого вы можете потратить 30 <Highlight>Шелковые нити кокона</Highlight>, чтобы выковать оружие <Highlight>[Ода сумраку]</Highlight>. <Highlight>[Ода сумраку]</Highlight> можно дополнительно перековать в <Highlight>[Тайное объятие]</Highlight>, предоставив недостающие материалы.\nПо ходу сезона максимальный уровень снаряжения для [Тайных объятий] и [Оды сумраку] будет увеличиваться, на что потребуется определенное количество <Highlight>Кокон Шелковых нитей</Highlight>.

=== [24] ===
CN:     您好{{先生|女士}}，您是想占卜，还是想加入我们俱乐部？
Old EN: Hello {Mr.{ Ms.|}}, are you looking for a divination, or do you want to join our club?
New EN: Hello {{Mr.|Ms.}}, are you looking for a divination, or do you want to join our club?
Cur RU: Здравствуйте, {Mr.{ Ms.|}}, вы ищете гадание или хотите вступить в наш клуб?

=== [25] ===
CN:     侦探{{先生|女士}}，如果还有疑问，不如先在房间调查看看。
Old EN: Detective {Mr.{ Ms.|}}, if you still have questions, why not investigate the room first?
New EN: Detective {{Mr.|Ms.}}, if you still have questions, why not investigate the room first?
Cur RU: Детектив {Mr.{ Ms.|}}, если у вас все еще есть вопросы, почему бы сначала не осмотреть комнату?

=== [26] ===
CN:     再见啦，温暖的{{先生|女士}}！
Old EN: Goodbye, warm {Mr.{ Ms.|}}!
New EN: Goodbye, warm {{Mr.|Ms.}}!
Cur RU: До свидания, теплый {Mr.{ Ms.|}}!

=== [27] ===
CN:     {{先生|女士}}，您是要拼桌吗？这边还有一个位置。
Old EN: {Mr.{ Ms.|}}, are you looking to share a table? There is still one seat here.
New EN: {{Mr.|Ms.}}, are you looking to share a table? There is still one seat here.
Cur RU: {Mr.{ Ms.|}}, вы хотите разделить столик? Здесь еще есть одно место.

=== [28] ===
CN:     前往香水店背后的幽静小巷，寻找接引人<h>莉丝·埃文斯</>
Old EN: Go to the quiet alley behind the perfume shop and look for the contact, <h>Lise Evans</h>
New EN: Go to the quiet alley behind the perfume shop and look for the contact, <h>Lise Evans</>
Cur RU: Идите в тихий переулок за парфюмерным магазином и найдите контакт, <h>Lise Evans</h>.

=== [29] ===
CN:     这位达文西先生和这位{{先生|女士}}！
Old EN: This Mr. Da Vinci and this {Mr.{ Ms.|}}!
New EN: This Mr. Da Vinci and this {{Mr.|Ms.}}!
Cur RU: Этот мистер Да Винчи и этот {Mr.{ Ms.|}}!

=== [30] ===
CN:     {{先生|女士}}，谢谢你帮我找回了这些，我会把这些都写下来。
Old EN: {Mr.{ Ms.|}}, thank you for helping me find these back. I will write all of this down.
New EN: {{Mr.|Ms.}}, thank you for helping me find these back. I will write all of this down.
Cur RU: {Mr.{ Ms.|}}, спасибо, что помогли мне найти их обратно. Я все это запишу.

=== [31] ===
CN:     {{先生|女士}}，不论您买了什么，本店都将利润的百分之五捐给济贫院，帮助那些可怜的人。
Old EN: {Mr.{ Ms.|}}, no matter what you buy, our shop will donate five percent of the profits to the poorhouse to help those poor people.
New EN: {{Mr.|Ms.}}, no matter what you buy, our shop will donate five percent of the profits to the poorhouse to help those poor people.
Cur RU: {Mr.{ Ms.|}}, что бы вы ни купили, наш магазин пожертвует пять процентов прибыли в богадельню, чтобы помочь этим бедным людям.

=== [32] ===
CN:     如果真是这个原因，{{先生|女士}}，能否请你帮忙照看下这位老先生。
Old EN: If that is truly the reason, {Mr.{ Ms.|}}, could I ask you to help look after this old gentleman?
New EN: If that is truly the reason, {{Mr.|Ms.}}, could I ask you to help look after this old gentleman?
Cur RU: Если это действительно причина, {Mr.{ Ms.|}}, могу ли я попросить вас помочь присмотреть за этим старым джентльменом?

=== [33] ===
CN:     谢谢你，{{先生|女士}}。这只是我的故事，也许别的骑士会经历更精彩的冒险。
Old EN: Thank you, {Mr.{ Ms.|}}. This is just my story; perhaps other knights will experience even more magnificent adventures.
New EN: Thank you, {{Mr.|Ms.}}. This is just my story; perhaps other knights will experience even more magnificent adventures.
Cur RU: Спасибо, {Mr.{ Ms.|}}. Это всего лишь моя история; возможно, других рыцарей ждут еще более великолепные приключения.

=== [34] ===
CN:     您好，{{先生|女士}}，很高兴能见到您。想吃点什么？
Old EN: Hello, {Mr.{ Ms.|}}, it is a pleasure to see you. What would you like to eat?
New EN: Hello, {{Mr.|Ms.}}, it is a pleasure to see you. What would you like to eat?
Cur RU: Здравствуйте, {Mr.{ Ms.|}}, рад вас видеть. Что бы вы хотели съесть?

=== [35] ===
CN:     \n……\n\n目前其余十人依旧下落不明。经过追踪调查，发现相关线索：\n1.失踪儿童年龄区间从八岁到十五岁不等\n2.失踪儿童最后目击出现地点主要在<Mark id="#159"> 西区 </>和<Mark id="#159"> 工厂区 </>。\n3.在案发地点附近，有人听到过疑似<Mark id="#159">笛子 </>的声音。\n4.……
Old EN: \n……\n\nCurrently, the remaining ten people are still missing. After tracking and investigation, relevant clues were found:\n1. The age range of missing children is from eight to fifteen years old.\n2. The last sighting locations of missing children are mainly in the <Mark id="#159"> West District </> and <Mark id="#159"> Factory District </>.\n3. Near the crime scene, someone heard the sound of a suspected <Mark id="#159">flute </mark>.\n4. ……
New EN: \n……\n\nCurrently, the remaining ten people are still missing. After tracking and investigation, relevant clues were found:\n1. The age range of missing children is from eight to fifteen years old.\n2. The last sighting locations of missing children are mainly in the <Mark id="#159"> West District </> and <Mark id="#159"> Factory District </>.\n3. Near the crime scene, someone heard the sound of a suspected <Mark id="#159">flute </>.\n4. ……
Cur RU: \n……\n\nВ настоящее время оставшиеся десять человек все еще пропали без вести. После отслеживания и расследования были обнаружены соответствующие улики:\n1. Возрастной диапазон пропавших детей – от восьми до пятнадцати лет.\n2. Последние места, где видели пропавших детей, в основном находятся в <Mark id="#159"> Западном округе </> и <Mark id="#159"> Фабричном районе </>.\n3. Рядом с местом преступления кто-то услышал звук предположительно <Mark id="#159">флейты </mark>.\n4. ……

